Matthew Lawrence Jani

linkedin.com/in/mattjani github.com/mahtDFR mattjani.com

Nationality: UK British

Location: Utrecht, Netherlands
DOB: April 11, 1990
Email: info@mattjani.com

A creative, multi-talented individual with an interest and passion for writing and technology. With several years experience in the technology industry, I am seeking a position where I can advance my skills within an innovative environment.

- Excellent levels of spoken and written English
- Strong technical abilities with knowledge of software development practices
- Analytical, problem-solving mindset
- Meticulous attention to detail with keen interest in quality and accuracy
- Pragmatic and solution-focused attitude
- Works well in a team and individually

Employment History

(2020-01) - Present Ultimaker, Geldermalsen, Netherlands Technical Community Manager

Working within the core development team of Ultimaker Cura; an open source slicing application that processes 3D data into 3D printable files. This software consists of components written in Python, QML, and C++, with millions of regular users worldwide.

- Maintaining GitHub repositories to track and resolve issues
- Using Jira to track internal issues and new features from idea to implementation
- Maintaining active community of over 100,000 users across GitHub and community forums
- Quality assurance of third-party contributions
- Coordinating software releases
- Managing localization
- Process documentation

(2017-07) - (2020-01) Ultimaker, Utrecht, Netherlands Digital Marketing Specialist

Working as part of a global marketing team, managing a global content calendar and cultivating content strategies based on different audiences.

- Writing short form content for web and social media, and long-form content such as blog posts and email campaigns to increase brand awareness and drive conversions
- Writing engaging B2B and B2C business texts with consistent TOV in line with the Ultimaker brand
- Copy-editing user manuals and collaborating with graphic designers for typesetting
- Producing technical content for engineers and end-users
- Managing content localization in 20+ languages
- Managing regular software launch campaigns
- Using digital asset management platforms
- Working alongside web development team to optimize content operation
- Demonstrating products at global industry exhibitions

Achievements

- Successfully implemented company-wide content localization pipeline
- Coordinated localization of Ultimaker.com into 7 languages

(2015-07) – (2017-06) DFRobot, Shanghai, PRC Community Manager

- Writing B2B and B2C copy to attract customers to the DFRobot brand
- Maintaining community forums with over 50,000 active users
- Curating social media channels
- Developing technical communications for products
- Maintaining pages for over 500 SKUs
- Product beta testing
- Representing company at exhibitions worldwide

Achievements

 Coordinated a successful crowdfunding campaign for flagship product 'LattePanda', which received 500% funding of the original goal

(2015-03) – (2015-07) EF Education First, Shanghai, PRC English Teacher

Preparing and teaching lessons to young learners

(2013-09) - (2014-11) Singapore International English, Jinan, PRC English Teacher

Teaching English vocabulary, grammar, and phonics to young learners

(2012-04) - (2013-07) Office Recruitment, London, UK Administrator

- Assisting with telephone enquiries
- Arranging interviews
- Managing customer database

Skills

- Python
- Javascript
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere

- Autodesk Fusion 360
- Atlassian Jira
- Git/GitHub
- Microsoft Office

Education

(2008-09) - (2011-07) University Of Kent, Canterbury, UK
BA (Hons) English Language and Linguistics

<u>Interests</u>

I have a wide range of interests, particularly in technology, DIY, and travel. My interest in technology has given me the opportunity to work in the Netherlands and in China, where I have developed my technical abilities and understanding of local language and culture. In my spare time I enjoy using Python to automate processes, as well as designing and 3D printing practical objects.

References available upon request.